Joseph Charles Muhler papers, 1919-1997 C356
Indiana University Archives
- Research, 1940-1992; undated (Box 1)
  - S. C. Johnson and Son, Inc. (Box 9)
    - Report (Box 9)
      - September-October 1974 (Box 9)
      - November-December 1974 (Box 9)
      - January-February 1975 (Box 9)
      - March-April 1975 (Box 9)
      - May-June 1975 (Box 9)
      - July-August 1975 (Box 9)
      - September-October 1975 (Box 9)
      - November-December 1975 (Box 9)
      - March-April 1976 (Box 9)
  - Self-Administered Brush-In, 1973; undated (Box 9)
  - Self-Administered Prophylactic Paste Clinical Studies, undated (Box 9)
  - Sherer Project, 1978; 1983-1990; undated (Box 9)
  - Soil Additives, American Oil Company, 1969-1971; undated (Box 9)
  - Soil Additives and Anticariogenic Foods, Campbell Soup Co., 1973 (Box 9)
  - Soil Additive Composition, 1970; undated; (Oversized See Box 24) (Box 9)
  - Soil Additives, International Minerals and Chemical Corp., 1970-1972 (Box 9)
  - Soil Research, 1969; undated (Box 10)
  - Sona Stream Battery Operated Toothbrush, 1971-1972; undated (Box 10)
  - Spencer (Box 10)
    - 1951-1956 (Box 10)
    - 1958-1960, undated (Box 10)
    - undated (Box 10)
  - Spencer Daily Records, 1957-1958; (Oversized See Box 24) (Box 10)
  - S.S. White Report (Box 10)
    - July-December 1976 (Box 10)
    - January-June 1977 (Box 10)
    - July-December 1977 (Box 10)
    - January-June 1978 (Box 10)
    - July-December 1978 (Box 10)
    - January-June 1979 (Box 10)
    - January-August 1979 (Box 10)
    - undated (Box 10)
  - St. Charles and University, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Stain, 1951; undated (Box 10)
  - Stain-College, undated (Box 10)
  - Stain J-LN-DD/A-B/O-P/G-K, undated (Box 10)
  - Stain Record A-B G-K, undated (Box 10)
  - Stain Record X-Z, undated (Box 10)
  - Stains, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - Stannous Fluoride Chewing Gum, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Stannous Fluoride Prophylactic Paste, China Chemical and Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Summary of Dental Services, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - Summer School Sophomores, 1955 (Box 10)
  - Sunkist Growers Correspondence Miscellaneous, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
  - Sunline Inc., Research Report, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Sunmark (Box 10)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 10)
    - 1975-1977, undated (Box 10)
    - 1976, (Oversized See Box 24) (Box 10)
    - 1976-1978, undated (Box 10)
    - 1978-1982, undated (Box 10)
    - Clinical Study at St. Vincent's, 1977-1979 (Box 10)
    - Research Report (Box 10)
      - 1974 (Box 10)
      - 1975 (Box 10)
      - 1977 (Box 10)
  - Survey Questionnaire-Michigan, Indiana, Ohio, IU Dentistry, 1961-1963 (Box 10)
  - Therapeutic Chewing Gum, W. R. Grace Co., Leaf Brand Division, 1970-1972; undated (Box 10)
  - Tin Fluoride Study, 1951-1954; undated (Box 10)
  - Tobacco and Health Research, 1961-1974 (Box 11)
  - Tooth Cleaning and Polishing Device, 1987-1989; undated (Box 11)
  - Tooth Incubation Studies, General Mills, Inc., 1967-1974; undated (Box 11)
  - Tooth Pro (Box 11)
    - 1977-1979, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - 1978 (Box 11)
    - 1978-1979, (Oversized See Box 24) (Box 11)
  - Top's Chewing Gum Company (Box 11)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 11)
    - Progress Report, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Toxicological Studies, 1974-1976; undated (Box 11)
  - Travel-Dahl, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
  - U.A. Charts, 1956 (Box 11)
  - United Dental Labs, 1971-1974 (Box 11)
  - V and W Patient, 1956; undated (Box 11)
  - Vick Report, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Windshield Washer Solution, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Worked Calculus Problems, undated (Box 11)
  - W. R. Grace Company, Leaf Bran Division, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Wrigley and Amurol, 1980-1987; undated (Box 11)
  - Yearly Report (Box 11)
    - July 1953-June 1954 (Box 11)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 11)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 11)
    - 1958 (Box 11)
  - Yearly Report Figures, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
  - Young Dental Manufacturing Co. (Box 11)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 11)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - 1974-1979 (Box 11)
    - 1975-1981 (Box 11)
    - Progress Report (Box 11)
      - 1973 (Box 11)
      - 1974 (Box 11)
    - Report (Box 11)
      - October-December 1976 (Box 11)
      - January-March 1977 (Box 11)
      - July-September 1977 (Box 11)
    - Quarterly Report, April-June 1977 (Box 11)
  - Zircate Treatment Paste, Caulk and Dentsply, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Zirconium Silicate Chewing Gum, Dow Chemical USA, 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Zirconium Silicate Dentifrice, Minnetonka, Inc., 1981 (Box 11)
- Publications, 1938-1984; undated (Box 12)
  - AAAS (American Association for the Advancement of Science) Paper Is Fluorine an Dietary Essential, 1957; undated (Box 12)
  - American Dental Association A Two Year Clinical Evaluation of Fluoride and Antienzyme Dentifrices, 1969 (Box 12)
  - The American Peoples Encyclopedia, 1967; undated (Box 12)
  - Amplifier Graphic Recording Method for Measuring Enamel Permeability, 1957-1959; undated (Box 12)
  - Anticariogenic Effect in the Rat of Cereals Fortified with a Soluble Phosphate, 1965 (Box 12)
  - The Arrestment of Incipient Dental Caries in Adults after the Use of Three Different Forms of SnF2 Therapy: Results after 30 Months, 1967 (Box 12)
  - B-C Clinical One Year The Effect of a Stannous Fluoride-Containing Dentifrice of Dental Caries Reduction in Children II Caries Experience After One Year, 1954-1955; undated (Box 12)
  - Bibliography, X-Ray Clinic, undated (Box 12)
  - Blood and Urine Fluoride Studies Following the Ingestion of Single Dosages of Fluoride, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Book Revision, undated (Box 12)
  - Caries Prevalence in Children of Low Income Families, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Challenge of Preventative Dentistry, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Chicken Soft Tissue Retention of Fluoride in Soft Tissues of Chickens Receiving Different Fat Diets, 1959; undated (Box 12)
  - The Clinical Anticariogenic Effectiveness of Supplementary Fluoride Vitamin Preparations—Results at the End of Four Years, 1967 (Box 12)
  - The Clinical Demonstration of Caries Arrestment Following Topical Stannous Fluoride Treatments, 1965 (Box 12)
  - The Clinical Effectiveness of Phosphate-Enriched Breakfast Cereals on the Incidence of Dental Caries in Children: Results after 2 Years, 1967 (Box 12)
  - The Clinical Evaluation of a Patient Administered SnF2-ZrSiO4 Prophylactic Paste in Children I Results After One Year in the Virgin Islands, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Clinical Use of Fluorides, 1962 (Box 12)
  - The Combined Anticariogenic Effect of a Single Stannous Fluoride Solution and the Unsupervised Use of a Stannous Fluoride-Containing Dentifrice, 1959; undated (Box 12)
  - Combined Use of Three Agents Containing Stannous Fluoride: a Prophylactic Paste, a Solution and a Dentifrice, 1964 (Box 12)
  - A Comparison between the Anticariogenic Effects of Dentifrices Containing Stannous Fluoride and Sodium Fluoride, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Comparison of a Single Application of Stannous Fluoride with a Single Application of Sodium Fluoride or Two Applications of Stannous Fluoride, 1961 (Box 12)
  - Comparison of Dental caries Prevalence in Three Cities, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Comparison of Single Topical Applications of Sodium Fluoride and Stannous Fluoride, 1970 (Box 12)
  - A Comparison of the Dental Caries Experience in Male and Female Rats Receiving the Same Amount of Cariogenic Diet, 1955-1959; undated (Box 12)
  - Convention Indianapolis, Dahl and Dudding and Display Topical Treatment of the Teeth with Stannous Fluoride Single Application Technique, 1958; undated (Box 12)
  - A Current Evaluation of Fluoride Therapy, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Current Therapy in Dentistry, 1963-1968; undated (Box 12)
  - C.V. Mosby Company, Notice of Reprints, 1959-1964 (Box 12)
  - Dental Caries- Orthodontic Appliances-SnF2, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Dental Caries Prevalence in Children of Low Income Families and Among Children of the Negro and Caucasian Races Who Reside in Either a Non-Fluoride or Optimal Fluoride Area, 1967; undated (Box 12)
  - Dietary Phosphates and Their Suggested Relationship to the Partial control of Dental Caries, undated (Box 12)
  - Dr. Muhler's Talk to Dental Hygienists (read by L. Dahl), 1955; undated (Box 12)
  - Early Identification of Promising Students for Dentistry at Indiana University, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Effect of a Stannous Fluoride Dentifrice on Caries Reduction in Children During a Three-year Study Period, 1962 (Box 12)
  - The Effect of a Stannous Fluoride Dentifrice on the Incidence of Dental Caries in Children One Year Following the Discontinuation of the Dentifrice, 1959-1960; undated (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Dietary Carbohydrate on Salivary Gland Function in the Rat, 1959; undated (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Dietary Iron on Phosphate Metabolism, 1959; undated (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Fluoride Administered on Fluoride Deposition in Tissues and on Serum Cholesterol in the Rat, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Effect of Gonadectomy and Sex Hormones on the Structure of the Rat Salivary Glands, 1953; undated (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Highly Concentrated Solution of Stannous Fluoride on Human Gingival Tissue, 1961 (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Oat Hulls on the Dental Caries Experience in Rats, 1957-1959; undated (Box 12)
  - Effect of SnF2-Zn3 (PO4)2 Cement on Enamel Solubility Using P32 –Radioactivated Human Enamel, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Effect of Sr89 on Fluoride Retention in the Rat, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Effect of Stannous Fluoride in Food and Drinking Water on Caries Prevention in Rats on High Sucrose and Coarse Corn Diets, 1950-1952; undated (Box 12)
  - Effect of Stannous Fluoride, Stannous Chloride and Sodium Fluoride on the Incidence of Dental Lesions in Rats Fed a Caries-Producing Diet JADA (Journal of the American Dental Association), 1950-1953 (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Three Different Fluoride Solutions at Different PH's on Caries Reduction and Fluorine Storage in the Rat, 1953-1955; undated (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Topical Application of Stannous Fluoride on Enamel Solubility when Pre-treated with Sodium Fluoride, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Effect of Topically Applied Stannous Chlorofluoride on the Dental Caries Experience in Children, 1954-1955; undated (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Using Different Clinical Examination Techniques in the Diagnosis of Caries Prevalence, 1963 (Box 12)
  - The Effect of Yeast on Dental Caries in the Rat, 1959; undated (Box 12)
  - Effect on Gingival Tissues of the Albino Rats of Concentrated Solutions of Topically Applied Sodium or Stannous Fluoride, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Effectiveness of a Stannous Fluoride-Containing Dentifrice in Reducing Dental Caries in Children in a Boarding School Environment, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Effects of Several Fluoride Reagents on the Surface Structure of Powdered Dental Enamel, 1953-1954 (Box 12)
  - The Effects of Sodium Alginate and Other Untested Polymers on Radiostronium Retention in the Rat, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Endocrine Influences Upon the Salivary Glands, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Experimental Clinical Human Caries Test Design and Interpretation, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Evaluation of Anticariogenic Effect of Mixtures of Stannous Fluoride and Soluble Phosphates, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Fifty Two Pearls and Their Environment (Box 12)
    - 1960-1963, undated (Box 12)
    - 1965 (Box 12)
    - undated, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Correspondence with Publishers Regarding Submittal (Box 12)
      - 1962-1964 (Box 12)
      - 1964-1974 (Box 12)
    - Dr. Muhler's Books, undated (Box 12)
    - Mimeo Copy, undated (Box 12)
    - Requests for Copies, 1963-1970 (Box 12)
  - Fifty Two Pearls (Box 12)
    - Chapter I: Introduction, undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 2: Tooth Development and Eruption, undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 3: Dental Caries, undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 4: The First Visit to the Dentist, undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 5: Use of X-Rays in Dentistry, undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 6: Dentistry for Children, undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 7: Orthodontics, 1959; undated (Box 12)
    - Chapter 8: Operative, Endodontia, and Crown and Bridge, 1963; undated (Box 12)
  - Fifty Two Pearls (Box 13)
    - Chapter 9: Periodontics, undated (Box 13)
    - Chapter 10: Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, and Oral Surgery, undated (Box 13)
    - Chapter 11: Prosthodontics (Artificial Dentures), undated (Box 13)
    - Chapter 13: Dentifrices and Oral Hygiene, undated (Box 13)
    - Chapter 14: Nutrition, 1963; undated (Box 13)
  - First Radio Program, 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fluorine and Dental Health Muhler and Hine (Box 13)
    - Book Rough, 1938-1945; 1952-1957; undated; (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - IU Press, 1959-1968 (Box 13)
    - Original Chapters, undated; (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Fluoride Excretion with Sodium Fluoride Vitamin Tablets, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Fluorine Paper for ADA (American Dental Association)Effects of Stannous Fluoride, Stannous Chloride and Sodium Fluoride on the Incidence of Dental Lesions in Rats Fed a Caries Producing Diet, 1949-1953; undated (Box 13)
  - Frequency of Food Ingestion, Toothbrushing Habits and Dental Caries Experience of Freshman High School Students, 1964 (Box 13)
  - Future Journal Material, 1958; undated (Box 13)
  - The General Practitioner's Responsibility in Dentistry for Children, 1951 (Box 13)
  - Historical Aspects and Purposes of the Preventative Dentistry Research Institute Current Dental Comment, 1969; undated (Box 13)
  - IADR (International Association for Dental Research) Abstract, 1966-1967 (Box 13)
  - The Impact of Preventative Dentistry on Dental Practice, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Importance of Type of Duet During the Suckling Periods on the Incidence of Experimental Dental Caries in Rates, 1948-1953; undated (Box 13)
  - Improving Dental Practice through Preventative Measures, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Improving Dental Practice through Preventative Measures, Third Edition, 1974 (Box 13)
  - The Incidence of Dental Caries in Hamsters Receiving Two Different Water Soluble Fluorides at Low Concentrations, 1952-1955; undated (Box 13)
  - Indianapolis Clinic The Value of X-Rays versus Toxic Effects to Dentist and Patient, 1953-1954; undated (Box 13)
  - The Influence of Communal Fluoridation Upon Dental Practice, 1967 (Box 13)
  - The Influence of Vitamin Supplementation of Fluoride Retention in Animals Fed a Synthetic or Stock Corn Diet, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Introduction to Chemistry (Box 14)
    - Report On, 1957 (Box 14)
    - Revision of (1964) Prentice Hall, 1962-1968 (Box 14)
  - In Vitro Studies of the Calculus-Inhibiting Properties of Tooth Surface Polishing Agents and Chelating Agents, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Katz-Muhler Lab Book An Introduction to Clinical Preventative Dentistry, undated (Box 14)
  - Laboratory and Clinical Studies Concerning the Development and Evaluation of a New Mechanical Toothbrush, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Laboratory Studies Concerning Fluoride Metabolism Using Two Different Types of Fluoride Tablets, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Laboratory Studies Concerning the Enamel and Dentin Abrasion Properties of Common Dentifrice Polishing Agents, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Laboratory Study of Biological Chemistry for Students of Dentistry, 1950; 1952 (Box 14)
  - Lack of Smooth Surface Caries in Rats Receiving Modified Stephan Diet, 1957-1959; undated (Box 14)
  - Manuscript for Journal of Dentistry for Children Studies of Prophylaxis Pastes Containing Sodium-Potassium Aluminum Silicate and Fluoride, 1975-1977; undated (Box 14)
  - Manuscript for the Journal of Dental Research Studies of Prophylaxis Pastes Containing Sodium-Potassium Aluminum Silicate and Fluoride, 1977-1978 (Box 14)
  - Mass Treatment of Children with a Stannous Fluoride- Zirconium Silicate Self-Administered Prophylactic Paste for Partial Control of Dental Caries, 1968 (Box 14)
  - A Mastication Device Designed for the Evaluation of Chewing Gums, 1981 (Box 14)
  - Metabolic Availability of Fluoride from Oyster Shells, 1959-1960; undated (Box 14)
  - A Method for the Collection and Measurement of Saliva from the Submaxillary Gland in the Rat, undated (Box 14)
  - Methods of Fluorine Analysis, undated (Box 14)
  - Muhler-Stevens Textbook, Why Dental Health Education?, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - A New Approach to the Topical Application of Fluorides in Children with Results at the End of Four Years, 1959 (Box 14)
  - New Fluoride Book, 1966-1967; undated (Box 14)
  - Nutrition Book, Lea and Febiger, 1953-1959 (Box 14)
  - 100 Years of Dental Education in Indiana, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Oral Hygiene Habits of Young Adults, 1955; undated (Box 14)
  - The Oral Tissues- The Barometer if the Body, 1959-1960 (Box 14)
  - Originals Past Scientific Articles for Journals, 1958-1959; undated (Box 14)
  - Outline, undated (Box 14)
  - Part I: Practical Preventative Dentistry, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Part II: Practical Preventative Dentistry, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Part III: Practical Preventative Dentistry, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Patient Reactions to Brushing Teeth with Water, Dentifrice, or Salt and Soda, 1960 (Box 14)
  - The Ph.D. in Dental Science at Indiana University, undated (Box 14)
  - Physical Characteristics of a New cleaning and Polishing Agent For Use in a Prophylaxis Paste, 1975 (Box 14)
  - Pigmentation Associated with Stannous Fluoride Therapy in Teeth Calcified in a Fluoridated Area, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Pigmentation of Teeth Treated with Stannous Fluoride and Its Association with Caries Incidence and Oral Hygiene, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Placenta and Salivary Gland Fluoride Transfer in the Rat, 1960; undated (Box 14)
  - The Placental Transfer of Fluoride in the Guinea Pig, 1967 (Box 14)
  - The Potentiating Effect of a SnF2 Dentifrice Following Topical SnF2 Application of Dental Caries and Enamel Solubility in the Rat, 1959; undated (Box 14)
  - Practical Chairside Dental Health Education, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Preliminary Draft of Ph.D. Thesis, undated; (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Preparation and Properties of Sn (II) Hexafluorozirconate, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Preparation and Properties of Sodium Dentafluorostannite, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Prenatal and Postnatal fluoride and Dental Caries Experience in Deciduous Teeth, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Present Status of Topical Fluoride Therapy, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Preventative Dentistry (Box 14)
    - Book Proposal, 1959-1960 (Box 14)
    - Proposed Revision (Box 14)
      - 1964-1966, undated (Box 14)
      - 1966 (Box 14)
      - 1966-1970 (Box 14)
    - Proposed Revision Chapter 15 Dentifrices and Oral Health, 1965-1969; undated (Box 14)
  - Preventative Dentistry Film Script, undated (Box 14)
  - Preventative Dentistry in the Daily Practice, undated (Box 15)
  - A Procedure of the Routine Determination of Fluorine in Potable Waters Containing Iron, Manganese, Aluminum, and Chlorine, 1953; undated (Box 15)
  - Prophylaxis of Dental Caries: Relative Effectiveness of Chewable Fluoride Preparations With and Without Added Vitamins, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Proposed Oral Biochemistry Book, 1965-1966; undated (Box 15)
  - Proposed Nutrition Book, 1960-1962 (Box 15)
  - Proposed Textbook, 1975 (Box 15)
  - Publications and Patents (Box 15)
    - 1966-1977 (Box 15)
    - 1966-1984 (Box 15)
  - Questionnaire Survey to Indiana Dentists Concerning Preventative Dentistry, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Questionnaire to Indiana, Illinois and Michigan dentists Concerning the Practice of Preventative Dentistry, 1966 (Box 15)
  - Radiophosphorus Metabolism of Different Phosphate Compounds in Different Experimental Animals, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Recent Advances in Preventative Dentistry, undated (Box 15)
  - The Relationship between Fluoride Ingestion and Urinary Calcium, 1957-1959; undated (Box 15)
  - Relationship Between Maternal Ingestion of Carbohydrate in the Rat and Dental Caries Susceptibility of the Progeny, 1959; undated (Box 15)
  - Relationship between pH, Age, and Concentration of Solutions of Stannous Fluoride and Sodium Fluoride in Decreasing Enamel Solubility and Affecting the Uptake of Fluorine, 1952-1954; undated (Box 15)
  - The Relationship of Iron Intake to Serum Phosphorus Fluoride Excretion in Children with Chronic Kidney Diseases, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Report of a Study Demonstrating Improved Oral Health through Education, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Responsibility in Children's Dentistry, 1950-1951; undated (Box 15)
  - Review of Dentistry- Questions and Answers, 1968-1970 (Box 15)
  - Shafer- Muhler Grant 807 (Box 15)
    - A Comparison between the Effect of Selective Salivariadenectomy and Selective Salivary Gland Ligation on Dental Caries in the Rat, 1959; undated (Box 15)
    - The Effect of Antihistamines on Dental Caries in the Rat, 1949-1959; undated (Box 15)
    - Effect of Desiccated Thyroid and Thiouracil on Dental Caries Experience of Adult Rats, 1954-1959; undated (Box 15)
    - The Effect of Irradiated Yeast on Salivary Glands and Dental Caries in the Rat, 1959; undated (Box 15)
    - Effect on Salivary Glands and Dental Caries of Different Agents Known to Affect Thyroid Activity, undated (Box 15)
    - Food Consumption and Dental Caries in Salivariadenectomized and Duct-Ligated Rats, 1959 (Box 15)
    - Growth Hormone and Thyroxine: Effect on Submaxillary Gland of the Hypophysectomized Rat, 1958; undated (Box 15)
  - Single Stannous Fluoride Topical Treatments, 1958-1959 (Box 15)
  - Some Observations Concerning Dentistry in Bloomington, Indiana During the Past 13 Years, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Stain Paper The Effect of Microconcentration of Stannous Fluoride Solutions on Dental X-Ray Films, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Stannous Fluoride as an Anticaries Agent for Topical Application in the Dental Office, undated (Box 15)
  - Stannous Fluoride Enamel Pigmentation- Evidence of Caries Arrestment, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Studies Comparing the Metabolism in Rats of Radiophosphorus Provided as Nah2PO4 and Other Inorganic Elements, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Studies Concerning the Antisolubility Effectiveness of Different Stannous Fluoride Prophylaxis Paste Mixtures, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Studies Concerning the Effect on the Dental Pulp in Dogs of a Stable Stannous Fluoride Solution Applied to Freshly Cut Dentin, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Suggested Improvements in the Utilization of Dental Auxiliary Personnel, 1954-1955; undated (Box 15)
  - Technique of Application of Stannous Fluoride in a Compatible Prophylactic paste and As a Topical Agent, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Technique for the Preparation and Use of Zirconium Silicate as a Cleaning Polishing Agent, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Textbook of Biochemistry for Students of Dentistry (Box 15)
    - 1964 (Box 15)
    - 1969, undated (Box 15)
    - undated (Box 15)
    - Biochemistry for Students of Dentistry Book and Index, 1964; (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Biochemistry for Students of Dentistry (Box 15)
      - File II (Box 15)
        - 1956-1957 (Box 15)
        - 1957-1958 (Box 15)
      - File III, 1959; (3 folders) (Box 15)
      - File IV, 1960-1962 (Box 15)
      - File VRevisions, 1964 (Box 15)
        - 1963-1964 (Box 15)
        - 1964-1968 (Box 15)
  - Textbook of Biochemistry for Students of Dentistry (Box 16)
    - Biochemistry for Students of Dentistry Rough Chapters, 1956; undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - A Textbook of Nutrition for Students of Dentistry (Box 16)
    - 1958, undated (Box 16)
    - 1962, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - undated (Box 16)
    - Nutrition for Students of Dentistry (Box 16)
      - undated, (6 folders) (Box 16)
      - Carbon Copies, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Chapter 1: The Oral Tissues, The Barometer of the Body, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 2; Function and Need for an Adequate Diet, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 3: Constituents of an Adequate Diet, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 4: Constituents of an Adequate Diet, continued, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 5: Means of Judging Nutritional Status, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 6: Digestion and Absorption of Foods, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 8: Special Problems of Nutrition for Children, undated (Box 16)
      - Last Draft, undated (Box 16)
      - Research, 1953-1958; undated (Box 16)